Plot # 862 Ayesha Residency 1, Jamshed Road, Karachi

Cell:+92 3212783871

Lead Software Engineer with 12 years of experience with solid understanding in all phases of software development this include and Analysis, Design, Development, Testing and Maintenance applications, Good knowledge of Building scalable microservices based architecture

Personal Information

Name : Sved Raza Haider Father's Name : Syed Akhlag Haider

Date Of Birth : 17th Feb 1986

Nationalitv : Pakistani
Cell : +92 3212783871

Email : srazahaider@vahoo.com
 NIC : 4210167829193

Executive Summary

- Total working Experience :12 Years
- Working as Team Lead ERP at Feroze1888 Mills Limited.
- Worked as Sr.Software Engineer at Systems Limited
- Working as Sr. Software Engineer at Contour Software
- Worked as Sr. Software are Engineer at Abacusoft Inc.
- Worked as a Software Engineer at Mixit Technologies.
- Worked as a Software Developer at Sidat Hyder Morshid Associates.
- Worked as an Analyst Software Engineer at Fohmics.

Professional Skills

Languages & Tools: Angular 7,.Net Framework (ASP.NET, Win Forms, C#, SQL, PL/SQL, Java

Script, XML, HTML JQuery, JQuery, Mobile), Asp.net Core 2, Identity Server

oAuth authorization, Angular CLI ,Visual Source Code

SqlGate.

RDBMS: SQL Server 2000/2005/2008, 2019, SQLite

Application/Integration Servers: Web Methods 7.1, IIS.

Software Packages: Visual Studio.Net 2005, 2008, 2017 Crystal Report, Enterprise Library, Entity

Framework, Microsoft Smart Client. DotNet Nuke 7. SiteFinity

Configuration Management: Tortoise SVN, Visual Source Safe, TFS, Git, Repo Servers gitlab

Operating Systems: Windows 9x/NT/2000/XP/7/10

Design Patterns: Generic Repository, Onion architecture, DI ,MVP, MVC, IOC etc.

Socket Programming: SOA & Web Services, WCF, Multithreading.

Professional Qualification

- Bachelor of Computer Science
 (BSCS) from Department of Computer Science University of Karachi
- Board of Higher Secondary Education, Karachi

D.J Govt Science College

HSC Examination, 'A' Grade, 2005

Pre-engineering Group-Mathematics, Chemistry, Physics

- Board of Secondary Education, Karachi
 SC Examination, 'a-1' Grade (84%), 2003 Science Group-
- Certificate in English & Communication skills By Venture Corporate Trainer

Cell: + (92 321 2783871) Page 1 of 5

Employment History

Feroze1888 / Xublimity Ltd

Jan 2018- Till Now

CRM

Role: Team Lead / System Desgin

Worked on the CRM for the F1888 as customer which covers all the phases from where inquiry made from the clients such as Walmart & Target & record the tracking of orders against inquiry till shipment is made to the client,

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code, analyzing existing business code.
- Daily scrum Meeting, review deliverables &Unit testing, assist QA personal automating process. Peer reviews .code reviews

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2017 SQL Server 2019, Windows 7,
- Angular 6 ,Entity Framework /Nhibernate IBM EBS, micrsoservices architecture

Loom Monitoring System LMS

I have designed the loom monitoring system, by integrating the physical looms data through devices to the database & make dashboards for the user showing real-time status of looms with all faults machine stop codes , interactively & real time

Responsibilities:

• Design & architect the whole system & its integration with other systems in feroze1888

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2017 SQL Server 2019, Windows 7,
- Angular 6 ,Entity Framework

Automating Central Cutting Textile Process to WebBased System / Machine Maintenance Systems

Helped feroze 1888 migrating legacy system to web based solution for central cutting along with weighment integration services to send receive real time weight of trolley & pieces of towels

Responsibilities:

Design & architect the whole system & its integration with other systems in feroze1888

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2017 SQL Server 2019, Windows 7,
- Angular 6 ,Entity Framework /Oracle interfacing

Systems Limited November 2015- Jan 2018

Vendor Portal eConnect, Mortgage Connect, LLC

Role: Sr. Software Engineer

Worked on the vendor portal for Mortgage Connect, Mortgage Connect manage Vendors, their Transactions, Ranking and Accounting in their proprietary suites called eConnect. EConnect is fat client application, used within mortgage connect main office and their different office locations,

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code, analyzing existing business code.
- Daily scrum Meeting, review deliverables &Unit testing, assist QA personal automating process.

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2013 SQL Server 2008, Windows 7,
- Angular 2 ,Entity Framework

PMO Techvista

Role: Sr. Software Engineer

Worked on different website for PMO Dubai, using CMS **sitefinity** & its support ,Fednet migration ,support to PMO Dubai infrastructure ,

Websites are

- Mocaf https://www.moca.gov.ae/en/about/about-moca
- SKGEP https://www.skgep.gov.ae/en
- UAEInnovates, https://www.uaeinnovates.gov.ae/

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code, analyzing existing business code.
- Daily scrum Meeting, review deliverables &Unit testing, assist QA personal automating process.

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2013, Sitefinity 9
- Angular 2 ,Entity Framework ,MVC for custom widgets

Contour Software (PVT) Ltd — a subsidiary of Constellation Software Inc

April 2014- Nov 2015

> NEWSTAR

Role: Sr. Software Engineer

NEW STAR Enterprise is a fully integrated enterprise resource planning (ERP) software system designed specifically for residential construction projects and business management.

http://www.constellationhb.com/newstar

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code, analyzing existing business code.
- Daily scrum Meeting, review deliverables &Unit testing, assist QA personal automating process.

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2013, ADO.Net Web Forms, SQL Server 2008, Windows 7,
- JQuery ,bootstrap ,JQuery Mobile

Abacusoft

July 2013 -April 2014

T-Mobile Incumbent/Competitor Analysis System

Role: Sr.Software Engineer

The Incumbent/Competitor Analysis software that facilitates and forecast the Sales and Purchase for a company by analyzing the resources to be purchased and their costing compares with current and outside vendors that are providing the services to the company giving the optimal cost of the service.

http://www.t-mobile.com/

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code, analyzing existing business code.
- Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2008, ADO.Net Web Forms, SQL Server 2005, Windows XP,
- Third Party tools Infragistics & DevExpress

WebeDoctor

Role: Sr.Software Engineer

WEBeDoctor automates the entire workflow within a medical practice (i.e. administrative, clinical, and financial

https://www.webedoctor.com/ functions).

Responsibilities:

- · Enhancing and developing new business code.
- Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Tools and Technologies:

Visual Studio 2008, Asp.net Web Form, Enterprise Library, SQL Server 2005/Oracle, Windows 7

Creative Circle

Role: Sr.Software Engineer

Creative Circle is online Recruitment Portal based on DotNetNuke Content Management System. Creative Circle is a specialized staffing agency that connects innovative advertising, marketing, creative, and interactive professionals with companies seeking talent on a full-time or freelance basis.

http://www.creativecircle.com/

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code.
- Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Oct 2011 - July 2013

Mixit Technologies

Mixit Order Management System

Role: Software Engineer

The front office trading system is an interface between Exchange, investors, and institutions. It incorporates appealing features and work on advanced technology which facilitates higher accessibility, ensuring immediate response and advanced order management.

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code, analyzing existing business code.
- Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2008, ADO.Net Win Form, SQL Server 2005, Windows XP,
- Third Party tools Infragistics & DevExpress

Back Office Client & Web Service

Role: Sr.Software Engineer

The BackOffice system is the platform that facilitates a brokerage firm for all its Accounts (Customers) Management and Trade Settlement. The system is developed in a way that allows it to be highly scalable and customizable.

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code.
- · Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Tools and Technologies:

Visual Studio 2008, Win Form, Enterprise Library, MVP, SQL Server 2005, Windows XP

Sidat Hyder Morshed Associates

Oct 2010 - Oct 2011

Recruitment Portal (www.workjunction.com)

Role: Software Engineer

Recruitment Portal is an online job site which connects talent with opportunity. Recruitment Portal provides services to the job seekers and employers by providing them one platform for job searching and hiring, respectively.

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code, analyzing existing business code.
- · Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Tools and Technologies:

Visual Studio 2008, ADO.Net, ASP.NET, HTML, JavaScript, SQL Server 2005, Windows XP

Look - Out (UCPlanet Bandwidth Management System)Role: Software Developer

Look-out a product from UC Planet use to be a add-on to office communication server 2007. It manages the call limit to any network, web base reporting and configuration, also has the support for farm environment of OCS server.

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code.
- · Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Tools and Technologies:

Visual Studio 2008, ASP.Net , ADO .Net, SQL Server 2005, Windows XP

ESS-HCM Sync (Web & Windows Service Sync Project)

Role: Programmer

This windows service is designed to Synchronize ESS and HCM databases. Database Table structure is almost same for both databases. The process is to first sync all the data from ESS to HCM and then HCM to ESS.

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new business code.
- · Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Tools and Technologies:

- Visual Studio 2008, ASP.Net, ADO .Net, SQL Server 2005, Windows XP
- HEB Mobile Inventory (Sync application with web and IPhone app)

Role: Programmer

HEB mobile Inventory is Web and Mobile based application whose Front end Interface is I phone and I pad apps it helps users keeping an eye on the Inventory with all authentications and sync services on Asp.net applications

Manage remote and mobile asset data with mobile inventory devices

Perform physical cycle counts.

Fohmics

July 2009 - September 2010

BRP (Business Resource Planner)

Role: Analyst Software Engineer

BRP is a desktop based ERP based on Windows Technologies. It is Multi Currency, Multi Company and Multi Plant written in C#.Net with backend independent. The current application has been thoroughly tested on SQL Server, MS Access and MySQL database. BRP offers the best of functionality at the costs comparable to mid range ERPs

Responsibilities:

- Enhancing and developing new flow code, analyzing existing flow code, using the available best practices
- · Plans and conducts unit and integration testing.

Tools and Technologies:

Visual Studio 2008, ASP.NET ADO .Net, SQL Server 2005, Windows XP

References, recommendation and appreciation letters are available on request.

Cell: + (92 321 2783871) Page 5 of 5